Then this last part,
在最后一部分
basically, we can add filters.
我们将添加过滤器
So, up here with this function,
对于这个函数
this was basically just returning the most popular recommendations no matter what.
它将返回最热门的推荐内容 无论是什么内容
what we know is from the nice part is from this ranked_movies dataframe,
我们可以从这个 ranked_movies DataFrame 中了解一些信息
which is now created and we can just use.
我们创建了该 DataFrame 现在可以使用它
Just going to look at that.
看看这个 DataFrame
From this, we might just choose specific years or specific genres
我们可以从这个表格中选择特定的年份或类型
and pull movies that fall into that specific set of years or genres.
并提取出特定年份或类型的电影
So, we have a date associated with them,
它们有相关的日期
and so we can check that.
可以检查该日期
Or we can check if these are like one or a zero or even pull from this genre portion.
或者检查这些是 1 还是 0 甚至可以提取出类型部分
If some particular text is shown in there,
如果这里显示了特定的文本
we could pull that to only return those movies.
我们可以仅返回这种类型的电影
So, if we wanted to create a function to do that, we might call it,
如果想要创建实现这种操作的函数
or at least I called mine,
可以称之为...至少我是这么命名的
as you can see from the text up here, popular_recs_filtered.
从这里的文本可以看出 叫做 popular_recs_filtered
You can see from the body up here,
可以从这里的正文看出
these are the things that it takes.
它将接受这些参数
So, it takes a user_id, n_top just like before,
包括 user_id、n_top 像之前一样
ranked_movies is what I had mine used up above,
ranked_movies 我在这里使用了它
and then the years and the genres.
然后是 years 和 genres
It looks like at least from this suggestion,
至少从这行代码可以看出
it takes the years and then genres as lists.
它将 years 和 genres 当做列表
Then you can then use those lists run through the values and pull
然后使用这些列表 遍历列表中的值
only the things from the ranked_movies dataframe that fall into those values.
从 ranked_movies DataFrame 中仅提取属于这些值的值
It might be easiest to look at ranked_movies.
最简单的方法是查看 ranked_movies
Basically, if we wanted to pull certain dates,
如果我们想提取特定的日期
we could say, "Okay,
例如
give me the ranked movies where the date is 2015,
“请返回日期为 2015 年或 2016 年
or 2016, or 2017."
或 2017 年的已排名电影”
So, you can see those dates down here.
可以在下面看到这些日期
If we do something like saying 2015.
如果输入 2015
Okay. So that didn't work.
Ok不可行
What if it's as a list?
如果设为列表呢？
Cool. Yeah. So, you can see that if I pass a list holding a date,
好的Yeah如果传入存储日期的列表
we only get those dates back.
则仅返回这些日期的电影
So, let's try 2016.
试试 2016
Great. So, if I pass a list with multiple of those,
Great如果传入包含多个日期的列表
I can get the ranked movies where the date is in that specified range.
则返回日期在此范围内的已排名电影
So, we might add that into this.
将这行代码添加到这里
Might say, "Give me the ranked movies where the date is in,"
假设我们想要“返回日期在此范围内的已排名电影”
and we just want this to be the list of years that they pass in,
我们希望这个是传入的 years 列表
and that'll be my new ranked_movies dataframe.
这就是新的 ranked_movies DataFrame
Then at the same time,
与此同时
we could look at the genres.
我们还可以查看 genres
This looks like it might be a little trickier because the genre can actually show up.
这个有点难
There can be more than one genre as you can see here,
因为可能属于多种类型
so like short, comedy, drama.
例如短片 喜剧 剧情
There's actually three genres here,
这里有三种类型
there's two genres here,
这里有两种
there's only one genre with this particular film,
这个电影只属于一种类型
which makes it potentially a little bit harder of a problem.
使问题变得更难
So, the way that I solve this,
我的解决方法是
so if we looked at the ranked_movies and we pull this history column and we say, "Look,
我们来看看 ranked_movies 如果提取 history 列
this is a one" if this particular movie_id has that genre or a zero otherwise.
如果 movie_id 属于该类型 则这里是 1 否则是 0
But if we pass,
但是如果传入...
let's say we want to get historical Sci-Fi movies and we pull both of those,
假设我们想要获取历史科幻片 提取这两种类型
then we're going to get both of those columns back.
则会获得这两列
Essentially, if this is an OR statement,
如果这是一个 OR 语句
so if the genre is I want history or Sci-Fi movies or another movie,
如果我希望类型是历史片或科幻片或其他类型
basically we would want this movie returned,
我希望返回这部电影
we would want this movie returned,
并返回这部电影
but we don't want these ones returned.
但是不想返回这些电影
We still want this one.
依然想要返回这个
We can't just look at this column.
不能只查看这列
Essentially, what we want to do is take the sum,
我们需要求和
and if this sum that's given back is greater than zero,
如果和大于 0
then that means at least one of this is in that movie.
则表明这部电影至少属于一种类型
But it could be three,
和也可能是 3
which just means multiple of the genre showed up.
表示属于多种类型
So, the solution that I'm taking is an OR statement.
方法是采用这个 OR 语句
Like, if it's history or it's Sci-Fi or it's one of these other ones,
如果是历史片或科幻片或其他类型
any of those, then give me the movie back.
是其中的任何一种类型 则返回电影
So, we can sort of see that with this part here.
也就是这部分代码的作用
So, I'm going to use this part.
我将使用这部分代码
So, basically, if this is greater than zero,
如果这个大于 0
then what I know is that
那么表明
the ranked movies for that particular row have at least one of those genres.
这行的已排名电影至少具有属于其中一种类型的电影
So, I'm going to call this num_genre_match,
将这个称为 num_genre_match
and then basically what we can do is the ranked_movies that we want back are
我们想要返回的 ranked_movies
the ranked_movies that have rows where the row has greater than zero.
等于包含行大于 0 的 ranked_movies
So, if this is greater than zero, we want those back.
如果这个大于 0 则返回这些电影
Essentially, we could just take all the columns back.
我们可以返回所有这些列
So, the ranked_movies where- and this is no longer these two,
这个 ranked_movies...这里不再是这两种类型
but in fact it's the entire list of genres that you give me,
而是整个 genres 列表
let's see how many there are.
我们来看看有多少类型
So, this sum is going to tell me how many of those genres show up in any particular row,
这个和将告诉我们任何特定行出现了多少种类型
and then essentially what we want to do is if that row has more than one,
如果该行有多种类型
we'll return that back.
则返回该行
Then, similar to this function up here with the top movies,
与上面的这个 top_movies 函数类似
we can just use this basically exactly.
我们可以直接使用它
So, up here, these are just creating our filters.
这些行是为了创建过滤器
So, this is one filter,
这是一个过滤器
this is another filter.
这是另一个过滤器
This takes in the years and genre, creates the top movies,
传入 years 和 genre 然后创建 top_movies
and then at the end,
最后
we just want to return the top movies.
返回 top_movies